Guide to the Fredericka Martin Papers ALBA.001
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
- Series III: Combat Personnel: Biographical Files and Correspondence, 1937-1987; 82886
  - Robbins, Albert, undated, 1971-1976; 82939 (Box 19, Folder 36)
  - Robel, Edward, 1938; 82938 (Box 19, Folder 37)
  - Robels, Gilberto Rojo, 1963-1971; 82937 (Box 19, Folder 38)
  - Rody, John, 1971-1976; 82936 (Box 19, Folder 39)
  - Rolfe, Eddie, undated, 1970; 82935 (Box 19, Folder 40)
  - Romero, Ernest J., 1982; 82934 (Box 19, Folder 41)
  - Rosenstein, Herman (a.k.a. Herman Gabby Klein) and Mildred, 1972-1984; 82933 (Box 19, Folder 42)
  - Rosner, Hyman, undated, 1969-1983; 82932 (Box 19, Folder 43)
  - Ross, Adolph (Buster) and Lillian, 1969; 82931 (Box 19, Folder 44)
  - Rubin, Henry (combat vet and lab technician), undated, 1970-1972; 82930 (Box 19, Folder 45)
  - Ryan (Swan), Williams G., undated, 1975-1979; 82929 (Box 19, Folder 46)
  - Sanborn, Blackie, undated; 82928 (Box 19, Folder 47)
  - Schafran, Jack, undated, 1951-1971; 82927 (Box 19, Folder 48)
  - Schiff, Sam, 1971; 82926 (Box 19, Folder 49)
  - Schneider, Ted, 1977; 82925 (Box 19, Folder 50)
  - Schofs, Frederick (Germany), 1968-1984; 82924 (Box 19, Folder 51)
  - Schuetrum, Walter J., undated, 1938, 1970-1979; 82923 (Box 19, Folder 52)
  - Schulman, Jack, 1975; 82922 (Box 19, Folder 53)
  - Shapiro, Saul Meyer, undated, 1978-1985; 82921 (Box 19, Folder 54)
  - Shipman, Evan, undated, 1957, 1972-1976; 82920 (Box 19, Folder 55)
  - Siegel, Joseph, undated, 1970; 82919 (Box 19, Folder 56)
  - Sims, John, 1970; 454633 (Box 19, Folder 57)
  - Siqueiros, David A., undated, 1971-1980; 82918 (Box 20, Folder 1)
  - Smith, Clive (England), undated, 1977-1979; 82917 (Box 20, Folder 2)
  - Smith, Randall (Pete), undated, 1968-1979; 82916 (Box 20, Folder 3)
  - Smith, Randall (Pete), 1980-1983; 82915 (Box 20, Folder 4)
  - Soule Echeveria, Carlos (Spain): Deportation, undated, 1949-1954; 82914 (Box 20, Folder 5)
  - Stamm, Morris and Eleanor, 1975-1984; 82913 (Box 20, Folder 6)
  - Stanley, Fred O., 1985; 82912 (Box 20, Folder 7)
  - Steck, Bob, undated, 1979-1980; 82911 (Box 20, Folder 8)
  - Strauss, Sam and Rose, 1976; 82910 (Box 20, Folder 9)
  - Stuart, Yale, 1972; 82909 (Box 20, Folder 10)
  - Susman, William and Helen, undated, 1977-1985; 82908 (Box 20, Folder 11)
  - Thayer, Donald, undated, 1971; 82907 (Box 20, Folder 12)
  - Thompson, Robert, 1965; 82906 (Box 20, Folder 13)
  - Tisa, John, 1971-1982; 82905 (Box 20, Folder 14)
  - Titus, William, 1938; 82904 (Box 20, Folder 15)
  - Valenzuela, Manuel: Includes letters from Spain (photocopies), 1937, 1980; 82903 (Box 20, Folder 16)
  - Van der Schelling, Bart and Edna, undated, 1941, 1954-1978; 82902 (Box 20, Folder 17)
  - Villanueva, Nicolas Ramirez, undated, 1956, 1969-1981; 82901 (Box 20, Folder 18)
  - Voros, Sandor, 1937, 1971; 82900 (Box 20, Folder 19)
  - Wallach, Hy, 1971; 82899 (Box 20, Folder 20)
  - Weber, Franz (Germany), 1937-1940; 82898 (Box 20, Folder 21)
  - Weber, Franz (Germany), 1947-1952; 82897 (Box 20, Folder 22)
  - Weir, Harry Oscar, 1938; 82896 (Box 20, Folder 23)
  - Weissman, Irving, undated, 1964; 82895 (Box 20, Folder 24)
  - Weissman, Irving, undated, 1965-1967; 82894 (Box 20, Folder 25)
  - Weissman, Irving, 1968-1984; 82893 (Box 20, Folder 26)
  - Wellman, Saul, undated, 1970-1985; 82892 (Box 20, Folder 27)
  - Wellnitz, Fritz (Germany), undated, 1970-1974; 82891 (Box 20, Folder 28)
  - Wesson, Neil, 1970; 454631 (Box 20, Folder 28A)
  - Wheeler, Bill, 1970; 454632 (Box 20, Folder 28B)
  - Wolff, Milton, undated, 1945, 1970-1985; 82890 (Box 20, Folder 29)
  - Wolff, Paul, undated, 1975; 82889 (Box 20, Folder 30)
  - Yates, James, 1978-1982; 82888 (Box 20, Folder 31)
  - Yates, James Oscar (England), undated, 1982-1983; 82887 (Box 20, Folder 32)
- Series IV: General Correspondence, 1937-1985; 82841
  Series IV. General Correspondence, 1937-1985. This series consists of Martin's incoming and outgoing correspondence from a range of friends, political figures, researchers and former Medical Bureau officers and organizers. Included in this latter category are Executive Secretary Herman F. Reissig, Evelyn Ahrend Kirkpatrick, James Loeb, Louis Miller, Harold L. Oram, Violet Robbin, John Sherman, and Charles Tobach who contribute information on the structure and activities of the Medical Bureau in the United States. Other correspondents include: Canadian Communist leader Tim Buck and his wife Bess, journalist Herbert Matthews, writer Joesph North and his wife Helen, and Gina Medem, author of a book on Jewish participation in the Spanish Civil War. Also included is correspondence from historians Gabriel Jackson, Peter Wyden, Robert Rosenstone and Herbert Southworth. Of special note is a 1945 letter Martin sent to Congressional Chair of the Committee on Foreign Affairs Sol Bloom protesting U.S. relations with Franco. Also included in this series are several of Martin's address books (with loose notes and lists of addresses) and a number of business cards of contacts and friends in many countries.
  - Ahrend Kirkpatrick, Evelyn, undated, 1937-1938, 1972-1981; 82885 (Box 20, Folder 33)
  - Aparicion, Maite, undated, 1972-1983; 82884 (Box 20, Folder 34)
  - Aronson, James, 1969; 444441 (Box 20, Folder 35)
  - Ayers, Dais re: Frank Ayers, 1938; 444442 (Box 20, Folder 36)
  - Baldwin, Roger, 1971-1974; 82883 (Box 20, Folder 37)
  - Belfrage, Cedric, 1971; 445267 (Box 20, Folder 38)
  - Berenberg, Samuel, 1945; 82882 (Box 20, Folder 39)
  - Berman Schweitzer, Rose, 1953, 1981; 82881 (Box 20, Folder 40)
  - Bloom, Sol, 1945; 82880 (Box 20, Folder 41)
  - Bogin, Magda (with translations of poems by Maria Tercera Sinfonia), undated, 1968-1982; 445400 (Box 20, Folder 42)
  - Brie, Dorrit, undated, 1978-1982; 82879 (Box 20, Folder 43)
  - Buck, Tim and Bess, 1972-1981; 82878 (Box 20, Folder 44)
  - Carse, Robert, 1969-1970; 82877 (Box 20, Folder 45)
  - Cashman, Brian and Diane, undated, 1975; 82876 (Box 20, Folder 46)
  - Chubieco Alvarez, Pedro, 1974-1977; 82875 (Box 20, Folder 47)
  - Escobar, Pilar, 1957-1972; 82874 (Box 21, Folder 1)
  - Escudero, Isabel, 1975-1982; 82873 (Box 21, Folder 2)
  - Fles, Barthold, 1976; 82872 (Box 21, Folder 3)
  - Gago, Valeriano, undated, 1974-1980; 82871 (Box 21, Folder 4)
  - Gallego, Dolores, 1974; 82870 (Box 21, Folder 5)
  - Giner, Consuelo (Frank Ayers' sister-in-law), 1978, 1981-1983; 445270 (Box 21, Folder 6)
  - Jackson, Gabriel, 1976-1979; 82869 (Box 21, Folder 7)
  - Jacobs, Douglas, 1939-1940, 1969-1971; 82868 (Box 21, Folder 8)
  - Keen, Judith, undated, 1975-1983; 82867 (Box 21, Folder 9)
  - Loeb, James, 1971-1974; 82866 (Box 21, Folder 10)
  - Matthews, Herbert L., 1971-1977; 82865 (Box 21, Folder 11)
  - Medem, Gina, undated, 1970-1980; 82864 (Box 21, Folder 12)
  - Miller, Benjamin and Judith, undated, 1937, 1972-1982; 82863 (Box 21, Folder 13)
  - Miller, Louis, 1923, 1936-1937, 1968-1975; 82862 (Box 21, Folder 14)
  - Moser, Dorothy, 1987; 454206 (Box 21, Folder 14A)
  - North, Joseph and Helen, undated, 1966-1976; 82861 (Box 21, Folder 15)
  - Nunez, Manuel, 1970; 82860 (Box 21, Folder 16)
  - Oram, Harold L., 1940, 1971-1972; 82859 (Box 21, Folder 17)
  - Parra, Louis to Deirdre Briggs, 1949; 446527 (Box 21, Folder 18)
  - Patai, Frances, 1989; 454188 (Box 21, Folder 18A)
  - Reger, Muriel (Briggs)(incoming and outgoing, various correspondents; with performance programs, clippings, and photo of Reger), undated, 1948-1963; 1973; 452586 (Box 21, Folder 19)
  - Reger, Muriel (Briggs): Poetry and Essays, undated, 1935, 1940s, 1958; 454679 (Box 21, Folder 19A)
  - Reger, Muriel (Briggs), from Edmund Wilson, Jun 4, 1954; 452587 (Box 21, Folder 20)
  - Reger, Muriel (Briggs), from Lester Epstein, 1952-1953, 1962; 452588 (Box 21, Folder 21)
  - Reissig, Herman F., undated, 1970-1974; 82858 (Box 21, Folder 22)
  - Reker, Mary Lou, undated, 1979-1984; 82857 (Box 21, Folder 23)
  - Robbin, Violet, 1970-1972; 82856 (Box 21, Folder 24)
  - Rosenbaum, I. J., 1975-1976; 82850 (Box 21, Folder 24A)
  - Rosenstone, Robert, 1967-1972; 82855 (Box 21, Folder 25)
  - Sanchez Hernandez, Nestor, 1975-1984; 452590 (Box 21, Folder 26)
  - Segal, Benjamin, 1956-1982; 82854 (Box 21, Folder 27)
  - Sherman, John, undated, 1937-1940, 1971-1980; 82853 (Box 21, Folder 28)
  - Simon, Ruth, undated, 1969-1983; 82852 (Box 21, Folder 29)
  - Solovy, Jonathan, 1981; 82849 (Box 21, Folder 30)
  - Southworth, Herbert K., 1971; 82851 (Box 21, Folder 31)
  - Tobach, Charles, 1969-1976; 82848 (Box 21, Folder 32)
  - Weisberg, Blanche, 1980-1981; 82847 (Box 21, Folder 33)
  - Wyden, Peter, undated, 1981-1984; 82846 (Box 21, Folder 34)
  - Zell, Rosa Hilda (from Cuba), undated, 1965-1966; 454191 (Box 21, Folder 35)
  - Zell, Rosa Hilda (from Cuba), 1967; 454189 (Box 21, Folder 36)
  - Zell, Rosa Hilda (from Cuba), 1968-1970; 459981 (Box 21, Folder 36A)
  - Zell, Rosa Hilda (from Cuba), 1971; 454190 (Box 21, Folder 36B)
  - Zell, Rosa Hilda (from FM), 1966-1967; 454192 (Box 21, Folder 37)
  - Zell, Rosa Hilda (to Cedric Belfrage), undated, 1965; 454194 (Box 21, Folder 37A)
  - General Correspondence: Incoming, undated, 1967-1986; 82845 (Box 21, Folder 37B)
  - General Correspondence: Incoming (unidentified fragments), undated, 1982, 1986; 82844 (Box 21, Folder 38)
  - General Correspondence: Outgoing, undated, 1965-1986; 82843 (Box 21, Folder 38A)
  - General Correspondence: Outgoing (drafts and fragments), undated, 1980-1987; 82842 (Box 21, Folder 39)
  - Address Book (Large) I., Undated; 452263 (Box 21, Folder 40)
  - Address Book (Large) II., Undated; 452264 (Box 21, Folder 41)
  - Address Books (Small, 4) and Business Cards, Undated; 452265 (Box 21, Folder 42)
  - Addresses for Emergencies (List), Undated; 452284 (Box 21, Folder 43)
- Series V: General Subject Files, 1937-1990; 82537
  Series V. General Subject Files, 1937-1987. This series consists of primary and secondary materials collected by Martin in the course of her research. Notable are correspondence, leaflets and brochures related to Joint Anti-Fascist Refugee Committee; correspondence to Martin from German volunteers held at Gurs Concentration Camp; correspondence and articles related to Jewish participation in the Spanish Civil War; clippings and notes related to aid to refugees and exiles; primary materials from the American Relief Ship for Spain and the American Rescue Ship Mission, including a donation booklet; and bibliographic sources on the Spanish Civil War.
  General materials on veterans and VALB are located in this series. The VALB files span the late 1940s through the 1980s. Particularly noteworthy are questionnaires sent by Martin and filled out by 36 veterans who were treated for wounds in Spain; memos, reports and clippings related to VALB and the Subversive Activities Control Board; programs and materials from VALB's 40th anniversary event honoring women; and notes and statements clarifying the relationship between VALB and Medical Bureau personnel.
  Much of this series is given over to the copious research notes Martin took at various repositories, chiefly at the New York Public Library and Columbia University. Martin obtained thousands of pages of photocopies from Columbia University's Spanish Refugee and Relief Organization (SRRO) collection in her efforts to document the administrative history of the Medical Bureau. [Note: These photocopies have been retained, however permission to publish these photocopied materials must be obtained in writing from Columbia University's Librarian for Rare Books and Manuscripts].
  The correspondence between Martin and Brandeis University archivist Victor Berch, who provided extensive research assistance to Martin, is a useful source of information on the course of her work, and on the establishment of the Abraham Lincoln Brigade Archives at Brandeis. This series also includes many files of articles Martin clipped from the Cuernavaca papers (chiefly in Spanish with some English), mostly on politics and culture in Spain during the 1970s and 1980s.
  - Abraham Lincoln Brigade Archives (ALBA), undated, 1974, 1980; 82840 (Box 22, Folder 1)
  - Alaska: Spanish Expedition to: Research Notes, undated; 82839 (Box 22, Folder 2)
  - Allen, Jay, undated; 82838 (Box 22, Folder 3)
  - American Friends of Spanish Democracy (includes some American Medical Bureau material), undated, 1937-1938; 454201 (Box 22, Folder 3A)
  - Asociacion de Avidadores de la Republica, 1979-1984; 82837 (Box 22, Folder 4)
  - Associazione Italiana Combattenti Volontari Antifascisti de Spagna, 1972, 1984; 82836 (Box 22, Folder 5)
  - Basque Nationalist Movement: "Los Agechados" (Comic Book Basque), 1974; 82835 (Box 22, Folder 6)
  - Basque Nationalist Movement: Clippings, 1970; 82834 (Box 22, Folder 7)
  - Basque Nationalist Movement: Clippings, 1971; 82833 (Box 22, Folder 8)
  - Basque Nationalist Movement: Clippings, 1972-1985; 82832 (Box 22, Folder 9)
  - Benefica Hispana, 1962-1970; 82831 (Box 22, Folder 10)
  - Bogin, Magda: Newspaper Clippings, 1981-1982; 445399 (Box 22, Folder 10a)
  - Book Project Contributions, undated, 1968-1978; 82830 (Box 22, Folder 11)
  - British Volunteers, undated, 1938-1970; 82829 (Box 22, Folder 12)
  - British Volunteers: Repatriation of Wounded, 1938-1941; 82828 (Box 22, Folder 13)
  - Canadian Volunteers: MacKenzie-Papineau Battalion, undated, 1969-1979, 1984-1986; 82827 (Box 22, Folder 14)
  - Canadian Volunteers: MacKenzie-Papineau Drama (Toronto Workshop Productions), 1980-1981; 82826 (Box 22, Folder 15)
  - Cannon, Walter, 1971-1974; 82825 (Box 22, Folder 16)
  - Catalan Leaflets and Correspondence, ca.1970, 1987; 82824 (Box 22, Folder 17)
  - Catalan Protest Song, undated; 82823 (Box 22, Folder 18)
  - Catalonia: Clippings, 1974-1982; 82822 (Box 22, Folder 19)
  - Catalunya: Comissariat de Propaganda Bulletins and Leaflets, undated, 1937; 82821 (Box 22, Folder 20)
  - Catholic Digest: Pro-Nationaist Articles, May 1939-Mar 1940; 82820 (Box 22, Folder 21)
  - Centro Republicano Español, undated, 1980-1983; 82819 (Box 22, Folder 22)
  - City College Volunteers-in-Spain Memorial Scholarship, 1980; 82818 (Box 22, Folder 23)
  - Clara Barton National Historic Site - Printed Matter, 1965-1967; 82817 (Box 22, Folder 24)
  - Cocteau, Jean, A Letter to Americans (pamphlet), undated; 444440 (Box 22, Folder 24a)
  - Comite de Ayuda A Los Presos AntiFranquistas, undated, 1974-1976; 82816 (Box 22, Folder 25)
  - Committee for a Democratic Spain, undated, 1968-1970; 82815 (Box 22, Folder 26)
  - Communist Party of the United States: Clippings, undated, 1963-1983; 82814 (Box 22, Folder 27)
  - Coordinado Catalan d'Associacions d'Ex Combatents de la Republica, undated, 1987-1988; 82813 (Box 22, Folder 28)
  - Cuban Volunteers, undated; 82812 (Box 22, Folder 29)
  - Czechoslovakia: Politics: Clippings, 1968-1977; 82811 (Box 22, Folder 30)
  - Daily Worker: Notes on Spanish Civil War and Aid to Spain, undated; 82810 (Box 22, Folder 31)
  - Eby, Cecil: Between the Bullet and the Lie, undated, 1969-1970; 82809 (Box 22, Folder 32)
  - Fascism: Clippings, 1971-1982; 82808 (Box 22, Folder 33)
  - Film: "The Good Fight", 1980-1985; 82807 (Box 22, Folder 34)
  - Finnish Volunteers, undated, 1976; 82806 (Box 22, Folder 35)
  - Franco: Clippings, 1955-1983; 82805 (Box 22, Folder 36)
  - Franco: Death: Clippings, undated, 1964-1979; 82804 (Box 22, Folder 37)
  - Franco: Jewish Relations, undated, 1937-1939; 82803 (Box 22, Folder 38)
  - French Volunteers: Correspondence and Notes, undated, 1964-1981; 82802 (Box 22, Folder 39)
  - Friends of the Abraham Lincoln Brigade, undated, 1937-1939; 82801 (Box 22, Folder 40)
  - German Volunteers, undated, 1963-1981; 82800 (Box 22, Folder 41)
  - German Volunteers: Gurs Concentration Camp: Correspondence and Notes, 1939-1940, 1970-1971; 82799 (Box 22, Folder 42)
  - Germany: Brandt, Willy, undated, 1970-1971; 82798 (Box 22, Folder 43)
  - Hungarian Volunteers: Rakoszi Battalion, undated, 1970; 82797 (Box 22, Folder 44)
  - Hungary: Politics and Culture: Clippings, 1966-1981; 82796 (Box 22, Folder 45)
  - Ibarruri, Dolores (La Pasionaria): Clippings and Printed Matter, undated, 1970-1979; 82795 (Box 22, Folder 46)
  - International Brigades: Anniversaries, 1983, 1986; 82794 (Box 22, Folder 47)
  - International Brigades: Clippings, 1937, 1946, 1976-1983; 82793 (Box 22, Folder 48)
  - International Brigades: 40th Anniversary (Florence, Italy), undated, 1976, 1981-1984; 82792 (Box 22, Folder 49)
  - International Brigades: 50th Anniversary, 1986; 82791 (Box 22, Folder 50)
  - International Brigades: Notes and Research Materials, undated, 1937-1939, 1965-1980; 82790 (Box 22, Folder 51)
  - International Conference on the Spanish Civil War, undated, 1978-1979; 82789 (Box 22, Folder 52)
  - International Labor Defense: Aid to Spain, undated, 1937; 82788 (Box 22, Folder 53)
  - Irish: Pro-Franco Irish Christian Front, 1936, 1984?; 82787 (Box 22, Folder 54)
  - Irish Volunteers, undated, 1976, 1980; 82786 (Box 22, Folder 55)
  - Israel: Commemarative Grove Honoring International Brigade Volunteers, 1972, 1984; 82785 (Box 22, Folder 56)
  - Italian Veterans: Agencia de Prensar España Popular, 1976; 82784 (Box 22, Folder 57)
  - Italy: Longo, Luigi, 1964-1980; 82783 (Box 22, Folder 58)
  - Jewish Participation in Spanish Civil War: General, undated, 1938, 1971-1985; 82782 (Box 23, Folder 1)
  - Jewish Participation in Spanish Civil War: Centner, Israel, undated, 1971; 82781 (Box 23, Folder 2)
  - Jewish Participation in the Spanish Civil War: Diamant, David: Correspondence, undated, 1973-1981; 82780 (Box 23, Folder 3)
  - Jewish Participation in the Spanish Civil War: Israel Veterans, undated, 1938, 1970-1986; 82779 (Box 23, Folder 4)
  - Jewish Participation in the Spanish Civil War: Medem, Gina, undated, 1937-1939, 1971-1977; 82778 (Box 23, Folder 5)
  - Jewish Participation in the Spanish Civil War: Polish, undated, 1939, 1948-1978; 82777 (Box 23, Folder 6)
  - Jewish Participation in the Spanish Civil War: Skorupinski, Misha: Correspondence, undated, 1972-1982; 82776 (Box 23, Folder 7)
  - Jewish Participation in Spanish Civil War: Toch, Joseph: Correspondence, undated, 1969-1985; 82775 (Box 23, Folder 8)
  - Joint Anti-Fascist Refugee Committee: "Anna Segher and Constancia de la Mora Tell the Story of the Joint Anti-Fascist Refugee Committee" (pamphlet), 1945; 82774 (Box 23, Folder 9)
  - Joint Anti-Fascist Refugee Committee, undated, 1945-1951, 1968-1972; 82773 (Box 23, Folder 10)
  - Joint Anti-Fascist Refugee Committee: Brochures and Leaflets, undated, 1945-1953; 82772 (Box 23, Folder 11)
  - Joint Anti-Fascist Refugee Committee: Hospital Varsovia, 1949-1950; 82771 (Box 23, Folder 12)
  - Joint Anti-Fascist Refugee Committee: Tickets for Paul Robeson Concert, undated; 82770 (Box 23, Folder 13)
  - Justice: Notes on Olimpiada Popular and Aid to Spain, undated; 82769 (Box 23, Folder 14)
  - Lift the Embargo Campaign, 1938-1939; 454636 (Box 23, Folder 14A)
  - Malraux, André: Clippings, undated, 1968-1979; 82768 (Box 23, Folder 15)
  - Marion, George (a.k.a. James Hawthorne): "The Siege of Madrid" (typescript), undated; 82767 (Box 23, Folder 16)
  - Marty, Andre, undated, 1970-1971; 82766 (Box 23, Folder 17)
  - Mexican Volunteers, undated, 1968, 1976; 82765 (Box 23, Folder 18)
  - Mexico: Ateneo Español: Clippings, 1975-1980; 82764 (Box 23, Folder 19)
  - Mexico: Spanish Republican Schools, undated, 1975, 1980; 82763 (Box 23, Folder 20)
  - Modotti, Tina, undated, 1975-1983; 82762 (Box 23, Folder 21)
  - New Leader: Notes, 1977; 82761 (Box 23, Folder 22)
  - North American Committee to Aid Spanish Democracy, 1936-1937; 454669 (Box 23, Folder 22A)
  - O'Brien, Mary Wallner: Reminiscence of Constancia de la mora (typescript), undated; 454202 (Box 23, Folder 22B)
  - Photographs: Notes on Identifications, Reproduction of, etc., undated; 1937; 1968-1971; 1976; 447810 (Box 22, Folder 22a)
  - Poland: Clippings, 1970-1977; 82760 (Box 23, Folder 23)
  - Publishers Contacted, 1977-1978; 454187 (Box 23, Folder 23A)
  - Refugees: American Rescue Ship Mission: Leaflets, 1940; 82759 (Box 23, Folder 24)
  - Refugees: American Relief Ship for Spain: Correspondence, Donation Booklet, Photocopied Reports and Newsletters, undated, 1938; 82758 (Box 23, Folder 25)
  - Refugees: American Friends Service Committee, undated, 1950, 1975-1977; 82757 (Box 23, Folder 26)
  - Refugees: Aub, Max, undated, 1972, 1981; 82756 (Box 23, Folder 27)
  - Refugees: Bosch: Gimpera, Pedro, 1974, 1976; 82755 (Box 23, Folder 28)
  - Refugees: Buñuel, Luis: Clippings, 1973-1983; 82754 (Box 23, Folder 29)
  - Refugees: Casals, Pablo, 1970-1979; 82753 (Box 23, Folder 30)
  - Refugees: Galleani Case (Photocopies), 1939; 82752 (Box 23, Folder 31)
  - Refugees: German-American Relief Committee, undated, 1940; 82751 (Box 23, Folder 32)
  - Refugees: German Exiles in Mexico, 1974, 1981; 82750 (Box 23, Folder 33)
  - Refugees: Gónzales Fleischman, Ernestine, 1954-1955; 82749 (Box 23, Folder 34)
  - Refugees: de la Mora, Constancia, undated, 1940, 1964-1980; 82748 (Box 23, Folder 35)
  - Refugees: Neken, Margarita, 1964-1969; 82747 (Box 23, Folder 36)
  - Refugees: Relief and Aid, undated, 1937-1949, 1978-1979; 82746 (Box 23, Folder 37)
  - Refugees: Sender, Ramón, 1943, 1972-1978; 82745 (Box 23, Folder 38)
  - Refugees: Spanish Doctors in Mexico, undated, 1969-1979; 82744 (Box 23, Folder 39)
  - Refugees: Spanish Exiles, undated, 1973-1984; 82743 (Box 24, Folder 1)
  - Refugees: Spanish Exiles in France, 1939-1940, 1970-1981; 82742 (Box 24, Folder 2)
  - Refugees: Spanish Exiles in Mexico, undated, 1962-1980; 82741 (Box 24, Folder 3)
  - Refugees: Spanish Exiles in Mexico: Clippings, 1939, 1959-1985; 82740 (Box 24, Folder 4)
  - Refugees: Spanish Exiles Return to Spain: Clippings, 1976-1978; 82739 (Box 24, Folder 5)
  - Refugees: Xirgu, Margarita: Clippings, 1969-1974; 82738 (Box 24, Folder 6)
  - Republican Government in Exile, undated, 1960-1980; 82737 (Box 24, Folder 7)
  - Research: Contact Information for Medical and Combat Veterans, undated, 1968; 82736 (Box 24, Folder 8)
  - Research: General Notes and Queries, undated; 82735 (Box 24, Folder 9)
  - Research: Book, "Proud within Ourselves,"Outline of Chapters and Appendices and Chapter Excerpts, undated; 454641 (Box 24, Folder 9A)
  - Research: Book, "Proud within Ourselves," Outline, Title Headings, etc., 454671 (Box 24, Folder 9B)
  - Research: Book, "Proud within Ourselves," Chapter 1, Drafts and Materials, undated, 1975; 454675 (Box 24, Folder 9C)
  - Research: Book, "Proud within Ourselves," Chapter 2, Drafts and Materials, undated; 454676 (Box 24, Folder 9D)
  - Research: Book, "Proud within Ourselves," Chapter IV, Drafts and Materials, undated; 454677 (Box 24, Folder 9E)
  - Research: Interview Subjects (Lists and Notes), undated, 1973; 82734 (Box 24, Folder 10)
  - Research Funding: General (I), 1970-1976; 82733 (Box 24, Folder 11)
  - Research Funding: General (II), 454196 (Box 24, Folder 11A)
  - Research Funding: American Philosophical Society, 1976-1977; 454195 (Box 24, Folder 11B)
  - Research Funding: Louis Rabinowitz Foundation Application, undated, 1968-1972; 82732 (Box 24, Folder 12)
  - Research Notebooks (Folder 1), undated; 82731 (Box 24, Folder 13)
  - Research Notebooks (Folder 2), undated; 82730 (Box 24, Folder 14)
  - Research Notebooks (Folder 3), undated; 82729 (Box 24, Folder 15)
  - Research Notebooks (Folder 4), undated; 82728 (Box 24, Folder 16)
  - Research Notebooks (Folder 5), undated; 82727 (Box 24, Folder 17)
  - Research Notebooks (Folder 6), 1973-1974; 82726 (Box 24, Folder 18)
  - Research Notebooks (Folder 7), 1977; 82725 (Box 24, Folder 19)
  - Research Questionnaire: International Brigade Veterans (Blank), undated; 82724 (Box 24, Folder 20)